Register of the Kenneth Rush Papers, 1937-1989
Hoover Institution Archives
- OFFICE FILE, U.S. EMBASSY, FRANCE, NOVEMBER 1974-MARCH 1977
  - Speeches. Typescript unless otherwise indicated
    - Speech, North American Treaty Association Defense College, March 27 (1975?)
    - Toast, Clos du Vougeot. Also a Franch translation and speech cards
    - Remarks, Franco-American Institute, April 23 (1975?)
    - Remarks, Rennes Museum, April 23 (1975?)
    - Remarks, dinner in Rennes, April 23, (1975?)
    - Remarks, Rennes International Fair, April 24 (1975?)
    - Remarks, American Women's Group Scholarship luncheon, May 12, 1975
    - Toast, Franco-American Friendship Group of the National Assembly, May 15 (1975?)
    - Remarks, opening of American Days in Mulhouse, France, May 21, 1975
    - Remarks, Suresnes Cemetery, May 25, 1975
    - Academie Diplomatique Internationale, June 24, 1975. Speech cards and a French translation
    - Remarks at a dinner in honor of the Minister of Foreign Affairs and Mme. Sauvagnargues, July 1, 1975
    - Remarks, Picpus Cemetery, July 4, 1975
    - Remarks, Sons of American Revolution dinner, October 16, 1975
    - President Ford's Thanksgiving Proclamation read by Ambassador Rush, American Church, Paris, November 27, 1975
    - University Club speech, December 8 (1975?) Themes.
    - "U.S. Policy on International Capital Movements," speech, French Chamber of Commerce in the United States, December 10, 1975
    - Remarks, French television first network program: Americana, December 11, 1975. With French translation
    - Remarks, tree lighting ceremony, December 15, 1975
    - "U.S. - French Relations." U.S. Army Association address, Heidelberg, January 29, 1976 (Folder 7)
    - "Independence, NATO, and Western Security," French Defense Institute address, February 5, 1976. Speech cards; questions and answers summary
    - Remarks, France-Amerique dinner, February 6, 1976
    - Remarks, Washington Birthday dinner, February 23, 1976
    - Proposed speech, Chamber of Commerce, Marseille, March 4, 1976 (speech not given)
    - Proposed remarks, U.S. Trade Center, March 8, 1976
    - "Current State of U.S. - French Relations," National War College, April 29, 1976
    - Remarks, an international festival, Mont-St-Michel, May 2, 1976
    - "America's Third Century: The International Economic Setting," Academie Diplomatique Internationale, May 4, 1976. With speech cards
    - Remarks, Suresnes Cemetery, May 30, 1976
    - Remarks, Memorial Day Service, American Cathedral, May 30, 1976
    - Remarks, the Association "Les Parisiens de Paris," June 3, 1976
    - "The U.S. Bicentennial - The History of a Revolution," Deauville, June 12, 1976. With French translation
    - President Ford's statement read by Ambassador Bush at Deauville, June 12, 1976
    - Remarks, Wooster (School) Program dinner, Roussillon, June 14, 1976
    - Remarks, reception at the Mairie, Arles, June 16, 1976
    - Remarks, Le Havre, June 17, 1976. With French translation
    - Remarks, Bicentennial reception, Vendome, June 19, 1976
    - Remarks, Tilly Bicentennial celebration, June 26, 1976
    - Press release about landing rights for the Concorde airplane, July 1, 1976. With French translation
    - Remarks in reply to the Prefect's toast, Lyon, July 2, 1976
    - Address, Lyon City Hall, July 2, 1976
    - Remarks, American Cathedral, July 4, 1976
    - Remarks, Picpus Cemetery, July 4, 1976
    - "Current State of U.S. - French Relations," Mid-America luncheon address, Chicago, July 28, 1976. Outline
    - Remarks, Lafayette Day, Chateau de Chavaniac, September 6, 1976
    - Statement, Academie d'Agriculture de France, November 4, 1976
    - Remarks, Ecole Francaise Libre des Attaches de Presse, November 4, 1976
    - Remarks, the Marine Ball, November 10, 1976
    - Speech to the British and Commonwealth Women's Association, Versailles, December 3, 1976
    - Remarks, Sons of the American Revolution, December 7, 1976
    - Speech to the American Club on current state of U.S. - French relations, March 10, 1977. Outline
    - Draft for Vice-President Nelson A. Rockefeller, February 23, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Travel
    - Schedules and itinerary, 1975 (Folder 2)
    - United States, July 18 -September 3, 1975 (Folder 3)
    - Spain, December 1975 (Folder 4)
    - Schedules and itinerary, 1976 (Folder 5)
    - United States, May 1976 (Folder 6)
    - United States, July 17 -September 1, 1976 (Folder 7)
    - Authorizations (Folder 8)
    - Reimbursements (Folder 9)
  - Washington Economic Community statement (Folder 10)
- LATER YEARS, 1977-1989
  - Correspondence
    - General (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Atlantic Council of the United States (Folder 2)
    - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1949-1977 (Folder 3-4)
    - Mattison, Jay L. See also Box 14, Correspondence
      - 1969-1970 (Folder 5)
      - 1971-1972 (Folder 6)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - 1975-1977 (Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of documents and letters from officials (Folder 3)
  - Interviews
    - ARD, German television, 1980 (Folder 4)
    - ARD, German television, on the tenth anniversary of the signing of the Four Power Agreement, 1981 (Folder 5)
    - With Dirk Rotenberg. Department of History, Free University of Berlin, 1989 (Folder 6)